Friends, I have done research on the results from ICICI Lombard General Insurance. Friends,
Doctor Sheikh Jan, who is already busy in his profession, also
invests by doing his own research on investment. Right, so today we will learn from Zaid Bhai
which is the best company in general insurance and if
he has done research on ICICI Lombard, then first of all
why ICC Lombard and then
what can we expect from ICC Lombard. Right, Doctor Zaid
Prayagraj. Welcome now to the stage. Sir,
let's go friend, as Sir has given me the mic, does
ICICI Lombard company have a
multi-bagger potential or not. If it does, then we will
talk about it further. If it does
not, then why waste time? The biggest
question is that before knowing any company, it is
most important for us to know its industry.
If that industry has a multi-bagger potential, then there is a
good company in that industry which will have a multi-bagger
potential, its leader company. Right, so
let's look at the industry. First of all, the
insurance industry, which is general,
we divide the entire insurance industry into two parts,
which are life insurance and
non-life insurance.  Life insurance or general
insurance.
Remember our first video about life insurance.
Subhash Bhai explained life insurance very well in HDFC Life.
And if you
want to know more about life insurance,
go and watch that video to know why we should
invest in life insurance.
Right, today
we will talk about non-life insurance or
general insurance.
In general insurance, mainly we see four types of
companies. First of all, government
companies, public sector companies, then private
sector
companies, in which private general insurance
companies come, then there are scandalous
health insurances, in which such companies
provide only health insurance and
lastly, specialized insurance
companies which provide insurance for some specific cause.
Right, if we look at this industry,
means non-life insurance industry, then the
market of India is
approximately 31.5 billion US dollars. This
31.5 billion US dollars is the
fourth largest non-life insurance
market in Asia and if we look at it globally, then
we rank 15th in the world as well. Right, in
that  However, if we look at our penetration,
what is the penetration of the non-life insurance industry? Penetration means
what percentage of GDP is the
premium being paid, then it is only at 1. Whereas
if we look at developed countries, then
companies like US and Korea have 9
and 5.8 respectively. Meaning, here we are
not paying that much premium right now. Similarly,
its second is how much premium are we paying per capita. So,
how much premium are we paying per capita?
Right now our per capita income
is approximately 2000 US dollars. Out of that,
we pay an average of 22 US dollars per insurance
premium. When our income increases
from 00 to 10000, then our
insurance here will increase. As
our income increases, we will see a
good penetration and a good density here.
It is confirmed that
this is the initial phase and
in the times to come, we can
expect good growth from this industry in the coming years.
How much growth can we expect?  This is a
big question. If we look at the past performance of the industry,
then from 2001
to 2008, the industry grew at 16.6%. Then
came the non-tariff era. In the non-tariff era, the
industry grew at around 15.5%
and this year too, the industry has grown at around 16.4%.
If we
look at this growth, how was the growth of the private sector?
Where in the 2000s,
we used to see only government companies
in the insurance sector, only 5% were non-
government companies, by 2008,
it
gave a market share of 36.6%. Now how did it become 36.6%? I
mean, here the growth of the private sector was
more compared
to the government companies, due to this its
market share kept increasing and the same
growth of 15% that the entire industry got, in that
too, our public
private players grew more than the government sector
and their
market share was around 2023  In 2018, it increased to 51.4%
and if we also look at it quarterly,
means nine months last year, the market
share of non-private players was 51.4%, which has
increased to 53.8% in this quarter,
means here we got this growth,
who played a major part in the entire insurance industry, these
private players, they took them, so it has become
clear to us that on
whom should our focus be, we should focus
on private players because the
growth of private players
is more than our players, right, this thing is clear, then the
next thing that comes to us is
who has the market share in this entire industry, the
top eight companies have
approximately 60% to 59% market share of the
premium, so only the top eight companies take, in that
too, who has the biggest share,
The New India Insurance Company and
this is a government company, right, this happened, then
who comes second, ICICI
Lord started very late, as the
government companies were working with the audience,
despite that, ICI started later
and  Still it reached the second position, so if
we look at the private sector companies as well, then
what are the private sector companies in this top eight,
we have IIT Labad, we have
Bajaj Allians,
we have ADFC Orgo and Tata AIG, these are
four major private companies and in this
which company is directly listed,
in this the only directly listed company is
ICICI Labad, right
comes at second position, Bajaj Allians, it
is not directly listed but if we still have to
invest, if we invest in Bajaj Allians then
how will we do it, friends, we will buy
Bajaj Funds, Bajaj Funds has a
share of Bajaj Allians, right, similarly we thought that if we have to take a
stake then how will we do it,
hdfcfund.com, two are private and two are from the
government sector,
who gets the biggest market cap, ICICI G,
who had the highest premium share,
New India Insurance, and
who is getting the biggest market cap,
ICICI G, why is this so because
ICICI G is of investors
They have more confidence in this company and
expect more growth than the government company.
Right, so now let us compare the private sector from here and see
what options we have in the private sector. We have only
two options, Star Health and ICICI
Star Health. This is specifically a health
insurance company and ICICI is
general insurance, that is, it
provides health as well as motor insurance and all types of
insurance. Right, here
we have, if we talk about gross premium, then the
gross premium of ICICI
GI is almost twice more than Star Health.
Right, then we have
next profit, so the profit of
ICICI GI is almost two and a
half times more than Star Health. Right, then
we have next quality parameters,
in which profit margin, profit margin is
also better than Star Health at
7.9. Then expense management,
management expense ratio, management
expense ratio means how much
expense the company is incurring on management, it is also as
much there  The lower the number, the better it is. So here
too, ICICI will be compared to Star
Health which is better. After this, what is our next
quality parameter? Claim Ratio. Which means
which company is settling more claims? So,
here the smaller the number, the better it is.
Here, Star Health's
claim ratio is better than ICICI GI. And
why can we see this difference? Because
Star is purely related to health insurance
and IC also has a motor insurance
component where a good number of claims are
seen. Right then comes the
combination ratio. The lower the combination ratio, the better it will be if it is
less than 100.
Here, ICICI is 105, which is
not considered a good combination ratio. Right, but if we
look at its trend, what was its last rate?
108. Here, there is improvement in the trend,
but it is not good. And that is why
we saw that last year when it deteriorated,
ICICI GI's stock was hit hard.
Right then comes to us and
quality parameters in which
Solvency Ratio: Solvency ratio of ICICI GI is
better than Star Healthcare at 2.5.
Yield to Investment Ratio means what is the
yield on investment income.
There too, ICICI GI has 7.5 percent and Star
Healthcare has 6.9 percent. Lastly,
return on equity is better than ICICI GI
Star Healthcare.
ICICI GI has a return on equity of 17 percent. Meaning,
from this overall quality parameter, we
understood that we have two companies. Out of the
two companies, ICICI is comparatively better.
So, let us know a little more about ICICI GI. It was
started as a joint venture in 2001 and today it is the largest
company in the private sector. It is the largest
general insurance company in the private sector.
Its
shareholding pattern is that
retail has only 11 percent in the shareholding pattern. Meaning,
who has the major stake? Big investors have almost
89 percent stake.  It is
with big investors mutual funds FIIs and promoters. If we
look at it historically,
it has increased its gross premium at a CGR of around 26 per cent in the last 20 years
and last year
it
collected a gross premium of around 2177. If
we look at the profit, then in the last 20 years
it increased the profit of 33 crores and
generated a profit of around 1729 crores.
These were the years in which it did not make a loss for two years.
But if we look at other companies in the same year,
other companies were also running in loss.
But once it entered
into profit, it continuously increased its profit.
Last year the profits had decreased.
Why did they decrease in 22? Due to Covid claim rights.
If we look at its reserves, because the
profits were continuously increasing,
it also made the reserves grow at a CGR of 19 per cent in the last 15 years
and today the result is around 9900
crores. After the reserve, if we
look at this reserve, then now we will see this nine month
result for which we  Wait, let's
talk about how the monthly results of this
company came out. Gross premium
saw a growth of 17.6%. Investment income, which had taken a
huge hit last year, remember
during Covid, there was a lot of problem in the day market
when it was badly beaten, but this
time it saw a growth of 17.9%.
Expenses saw a growth of 12.9%
and in profit we saw a
growth of 8.3%. Where did this gross premium come
from? Its revenue mainly
came from motor insurance
and health insurance.
In motor insurance, we saw a growth of only 3%
and in health insurance, we saw a growth of
33%. Health insurance
saw a good growth, but
we did not see very good growth in motor, from
where its biggest revenue comes.
We should keep this thing in mind that
we have not seen good growth in the biggest expense,
right? If we
look at the expenses,
what is the biggest expense of any insurance company,
its claims, in which  There was a growth of 14 percent,
right, so this was the result of nine months.
After this nine-month result, we should see
what its trend is, whether it is getting
better or worse.
If we look at the trend,
last year the gross premium growth at the year-end was
17.3 percent. In quarter one, there was a
growth of 19.7 percent in H1, there was a growth of 19 percent and
this time there is a growth of 17.6 percent in the new month. So we
can expect that
this year we will see a growth of around 18 percent. Right, if we
look at the profit trend, last year
we saw a growth of 36 percent. Currently
in quarter one, there was a growth of 11.7 percent in H1, there was a
growth of 33 percent. Currently, we can expect a
growth of 7 percent.
So, what should be our
expectation here? In the short term,
we expect premium to grow at 18 percent
and profit to
grow at 7 percent.  In the long term, we
expect that the company should
show growth in its premium and profit from 13 onwards.
Accordingly, what should be our future
expectation?
What should be the future projections?
In future projections, we see that the
premium of Rs 2772 crores that came in 2023, we
expect that it should
generate a premium of around Rs 25,691 crores in 2024 and the
same should collect a premium of around Rs 98,500 crores in 2035. If we
look at the profit, our expectation is
that the profit of Rs 1730-1729 crores in 2023 should become Rs
1850 crores
and in 2035, we expect this profit to increase and
touch a profit of around Rs 15,000 crores.
Accordingly,
what does our fair value become?
Accordingly, our fair value of 2024 will be around Rs
1123 crores.  It comes to 1123, and by
2035, we are expecting the same
fair value to increase to around 12, 1200, 1200, 12000. Is
this company
available at its fair value? So let's
look at the charts. We can
see that as per the valuation, the
forward P is 40 and
PG is 6. Meaning, according to this, the
company is getting a little expensive right now. If we
get to buy it around 1150, then it will be a very
good accretion zone. So, we
will collect it near 1150 and
we keep our short term target at around 1775.
And we keep such stocks with us for a multi rally. The
things we have to keep in mind in this entire presentation are
growth, but the major thing is that
good growth has not been seen from motor there yet. The
combination
ratio has improved, but it
is still above 100. Right?  If this stock corrects,
then we should
collect it at a good price and keep
such stocks in our hold for a multi-year rally.
What should be the portfolio allocation of this stock? 2%
allocation is sufficient. If we
get good growth in future, we will increase it, if we don't get it, we will
reduce it. Right, and this was
our presentation about ICICI.
This is only for educational purpose. This is
not a buying and selling tip. Please do
your own research. Thank you very much
JD Bhai. You explained very well
about the general insurance industry. The
things that I noted, I think,
during your presentation, you told that general insurance will
grow, so I want growth and I can get that
growth of 15% here.
Provided as you said,
if we invest in private insurance, then let me make
one thing clear. JD Bhai, they are
not telling you which policy to take.
No, it is not like that, take the policy of New India Insurance. There is nothing like that,
you have to ask your agent. We will discuss their details.  If we were
doing analysis, we wanted growth. So
Zaid Bhai said, come to private sector. There are
many companies in private sector where
we got the information. Who is the leader?
ICSE Lombard. Second, who has the leadership? Right,
you stay with the leader,
friends. You get growth. There are
benefits in the future. You saw the entire history,
how it has given both consistent profitability and growth.
I will share my personal
experience with you friends. When
its IPO came, right, we
saw good growth. We invested money at the time of IPO. It
tripled in the first three years. So
everyone knows what the hot tip was at that time.
Hey friend, buy ICSE Lombard.
Look how much it is running.
Friends, people forget that
if that has happened in nine years, it has tripled in three years. So,
every rally also has a correction. There is
no need to worry about other signs of correction. It has not been running for nine
years. For the last three
years, Life General and all these companies
were in correction and were going through challenging mode.
Bhai told you very good points. Look, see.
Last year, the bond market
challenged you, this year you are seeing a recovery,
like 16% growth in premium,
you told me, good growth, friend, 16% growth, good
growth, that growth, profitability is improving,
so let us look at the near term,
we still haven't invested life time, have we
not, if someone bought it last year, then
he must have got 40, maybe it rallied like 40, then
he would say it went very well, if
someone bought it two years ago, he saw that 50 was broken, 40, what did he get, nothing,
right, so
in such two years there is nothing, but it's right
friends, your shares are going to run like this, they will
rally for three-four years, they will continue to rally, they will
correct for three-four years, let it
correct, do SIP at such times, so you need to do
SIP in the coming time, like
life general, there will be stability in all these,
profitability will increase, friends, your shares have to
run, so this is a very good time
to allocate this type of share, rate brother,
not equal sir, thank you sir, and some more
Give information about investment income,
how much investment income was made,
approximately around 11000 crore cases, approximately 11000
crore so look, this is your safety, people
think that general rent has been increased, man,
premiums come, there are a lot of claims, but
look, companies are also taking care of safety, now they have started getting
investment income of 10 thousand crores,
this is just the beginning, these people keep investing,
friends, 80-90% of their money is
invested in the debt market, the rest is invested
in the stock market, I just
read the ICC update that they invested
approximately, I am saying maybe
around 200 crores, they
invested in HDFC Life, now
HDFC Life is a different segment, life
insurance, they will also
get something in profitability, they invested around 200 crores
in E industry, this month they
invested around 100 crores in Karnataka Bank, so these
people are also building portfolios like you, they are
investing money in equity, right, so
you get income from both the types, the company makes
profits  Yes and
you get the benefit of this investment income in the long term. According to me,
if I remain invested,
I can get consistent dividends throughout my life.
Right, so thank you very much Jan Bhai.
And if I have forgotten any input, can you tell me?
No sir, it is almost covered. So stay tuned. Right now, it seems to be in an
uptrend
and it seems to burst. It is yet to come in the future.
Great, great, okay, so thank you very much to
Said Bhai.